Guide to the Donald Davie Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Donald Davie papers
1926-2005
1970-1990
GEN MSS 439
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
24.68
(45 boxes) + 5 broadside folders
Correspondence consists mainly of letters to Davie from poets, literary critics, and publishers discussing the literary world, the academic environment, Davie's writings, and the writing of others. Writings include research materials, drafts, and clippings of reviews for books by Davie; drafts of articles, lectures, poems, and reviews by Davie; and writings by others. The collection also includes journals and notebooks by Davie that contain notes and drafts of writings. There are some personal papers, such as biographical clippings, as well as a few subject files on literary people.
Davie, Donald, 1922-1995
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Anthony Garnett, 1984-1996.
June 2013 Acquisition: purchased from Anthony Garnett on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 30 (correspondence from Charles Tomlinson): Restricted during the lifetime of Charles Tomlinson.
Boxes 31-32: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Box 45 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Donald Davie (1922-1995)
Donald Davie, a poet, literary critic, and teacher, was born in Barnsley in Yorkshire, England on 17 July 1922. His service in the Royal Navy during World War II, which sent him to Russia, sparked an interest in Russian literature; he later wrote his doctoral dissertation and other works on that subject, including Slavic Excursions: Essays on Russian and Polish Literature. Davie married Doreen John in 1945; they later had three children. He received his bachelor's degree in 1947 and his doctoral degree in 1951, both from the University of Cambridge. His teaching career began at Trinity College, Dublin, in 1950. He went on to teach at the University of Cambridge from 1958 to 1964, and at the University of Essex from 1964 to 1968. That year, Davie left England for the United States, where he taught at Stanford University for ten years. He then taught at Vanderbilt University until 1988, when he retired and returned to England. Davie's work includes poetry collections, such as Brides of Reason, Essex Poems, 1963-67, and To Scorch or Freeze, as well as literary criticism, such as Purity of Diction in English Verse and Ezra Pound: Poet as Sculptor. Davie died on 18 September 1995 in Exeter in Devon, England.
Scope and Contents
The Donald Davie Papers document the work of the British poet and literary critic, Donald Davie (1922-1995). The papers consist of correspondence; manuscripts and notes for articles, books, lectures, poems, and reviews; clippings of reviews of Davie's books; journals and notebooks; biographical materials; and subject files. The collection spans the years 1926 to 1995, but the bulk of the material is from the 1970s to the 1990s. The collection is organized into four series: Correspondence, Writings, Journals and Notebooks, and Other Papers. It is housed in 32 boxes.
Series I, Correspondence, mainly contains letters to Davie, although there are also some drafts of letters from him. The letters are from poets, literary critics, and publishers. The letters discuss the literary world, the academic environment, Davie's writing, and the writing of others. Correspondents include Michael J. Alexander, Massimo Bacigalupo, Martin Dodsworth, Reginald Gibbons, Thom Gunn, Eva Hesse, Angela Livingstone, Samuel Menashe, George Oppen, Robert Pinsky, Michael Schmidt, C. H. Sisson, and Clive Wilmer, among others. Some of the letters (for example, those from Janet Lewis) are also addressed to Doreen Davie. There are three files of correspondence regarding the Yeats International Summer School.
Series II, Writings, is organized into seven subseries: Articles, Books, Lectures, Poems, Reviews, Other Writings, and Writings of Others. The first subseries, Articles, contains holograph and typescript drafts, as well as printed versions, of articles by Davie. Topics range from poetry and literary criticism to memorials of other authors and comments on Davie's role in society. The second subseries, Books, contains research materials, drafts, and clipping of reviews for books by Davie. Included are drafts for Essex Poems, 1963-67, Kenneth Allott and the Thirties, The Psalms in English, Purity of Diction in English Verse, and Thomas Hardy and British Poetry, among others.
The third subseries, Lectures, contains holograph and typescript drafts of lectures that Davie gave on poetry and literary criticism from 1969 to 1992. Most of the lectures were given at universities; there are also two lectures from the Yeats International Summer School, and one lecture for radio. The fourth subseries, Poems, contains holograph and typescript drafts of poems by Davie. They are arranged alphabetically by title (there is one file of untitled poems); most are undated. There is also a scrapbook that contains clippings of poems published by Davie. Any poems that were arranged by Davie as a draft for a book of poetry are filed in the subseries, Books.
The fifth subseries, Reviews, contains reviews by Davie of books by other poets and literary critics. If the review has a title, it is filed under that title; if there is no title, it is filed under the last name of the author of the book being reviewed. Some of the reviews are holograph and typescript drafts; others are printed versions. The sixth subseries, Other Writings, contains six letters to editors of newspapers and journals; Davie's doctoral dissertation, "The English Idea of Russian Fiction Since 1828"; translations by Davie of poems by others; and editorials that Davie wrote for Poetry Nation Review from 1977 to 1981. The seventh subseries, Writings of Others, contains writings by other poets and literary critics, including Geoffrey Hill, Michael Schmidt, Charles Tomlinson, and Yvor Winters, among others. Some of the writings are typescript drafts; others are printed versions.
Series III, Journals and Notebooks, is arranged chronologically. The journals and notebooks are all written in Davie's hand in volumes; most were given volume numbers and were dated by Davie. Some of the volumes contain drafts of writings by Davie, such as poems and articles. Other volumes contain Davie's notes for his writings (for example, on Ezra Pound), as well as his notes on the writings of others. The series spans the years 1947 to 1995.
Series IV, Other Papers, is organized into two subseries: Personal Papers, and Subject Files. Personal Papers contains biographical material about Davie, including clippings, two interviews, an article he wrote for Contemporary Authors, and a photograph of members of the Davie family. There is also some information about a photography exhibition in 1985 by Doreen Davie. Subject Files contains a few files of clippings, notes, and printed versions of articles, mainly about literary people. There are also files about the Poetry International conference in 1967, and the Yeats International Summer School. (Correspondence for the latter is located in Series I, box 8, folders 366-368).
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Correspondence, 1957-1995. II. Writings, 1946-1995. III. Journals and Notebooks, 1947-1995. IV. Other Papers, 1926-1992. V. June 2013 Acquisition, 1940-2005.
Critics -- England -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, English -- 20th Century -- Archives; Diaries; Lectures; Critics -- England; Poets -- England; Alexander, Michael J.; Bacigalupo, Massimo, 1947-; Davie, Donald, 1922-1995; Dodsworth, Martin; Gibbons, Reginald, 1947-; Gunn, Thom, 1929-; Hesse, Eva, 1936-1970; Lewis, Janet, 1899-1998; Livingstone, Angela, 1934-; Menashe, Samuel, 1925-2011; Oppen, George, 1908-1984; Pinsky, Robert, 1940-; Schmidt, Michael, 1947-; Sisson, C. H. (Charles Hubert), 1914-2003; Wilmer, Clive, 1945-; Yeats International Summer School
- Correspondence, 1957-1995; Series I; 3.2; (8 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by last name. Letters from correspondents not listed individually may be found in "letter" general files; unidentified correspondence is arranged at the end.
  - "A" general, 1982-93, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abse, Dannie, 1983 Sep 26 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agenda, 1986-95 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Contains letters from William Cookson.
  - Alexander, Michael J., 1971-94, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allott, Miriam Farris, 1980, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The American Scholar, 1975 Feb 7 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Anania, Michael, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Archibald, Douglas N.
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: Series IV, Yeats International Summer School, box 29, folders 736-741
  - Arkins, Brian, n.y. Nov 12 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    See also: Series IV, Yeats International Summer School, box 29, folders 736-741
  - Arts Council of Great Britain, 1993 Jun 4 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ashby, Cliff, 1979, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Australian National University. Humanities Research Centre, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ayrton, Elisabeth, 1976 Nov 9 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "B" general, 1970-94, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - Bacigalupo, Massimo, 1981-90 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bailey, Les, 1983-89 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Baranczak, Stanislaw, 1987 Sep 28 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Barfoot, C. C., 1995 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Barnett, Anthony, 1989 Jan 19 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Barrell, John, 1973-85 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bart-Williams, Gaston
  - Barton, Edwin J., 1992 Sep 10 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Basney, Lionel, n.y. Sep 14 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bassani, Giorgio, 1968 Dec 12 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bateson, F. W., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bayley, John, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bedford, William, 1973 Mar 2 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bedient, Calvin, 1977 Mar 6 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - The Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 1974 Dec 11 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bell, Madison Smartt, [1985] (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bennet, Glin, 1983 Nov 3 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bergonzi, Bernard, 1977-92 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bernstein, Michael André, 1986 Feb 16 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Berry, Wendell, 1988 May 27 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Betjeman, John, Sir, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Binfield, Clyde, 1976 Dec 17 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Birmingham Museums and Art Gallery, 1992 Jul 1 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Birns, Nicholas, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Black Mesa Press, [1980] Oct 1 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Bloom, Harold, 1975 Aug 30 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Bobyshev, Dimitrii, 1986-87 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Bold, Alan Norman, 1983 Nov 4 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Bowers, Edgar, 1987 Nov 1 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Bowers, Neal, 1985 Oct 1 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Bowra, C. M., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - British Academy, 1987-94 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Contains letters from Philip Edwards and Howard Erskine-Hill.
  - Bronowski, Jacob, 1968-69 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Brooke-Rose, Christine, 1968-70 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Brooks, Cleanth, 1990, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Brotherston, Gordon, 1969, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Brown, Clarence, 1981, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Brown, Mark, 1990-94 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Brumbaum, Harold, 1972-95, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 52-53)
    Letter dated 1995 Jun 26 encloses photo of Brumbaum, DD, and Doreen Davie.
  - Buckley, Christopher, 1986 Jan 25 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Bunting, Basil, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Two photocopies of letters from Bunting: 1975 Sep 25 (annotated by DD) and 1975 Oct 9.
  - Bushnell, O. A., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - "C" general, 1965-88 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Caddel, Richard, 1987 Feb 16 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - The Cambridge Review, 1986, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    Contains letters from Ruth Morse.
  - Cambridge University Press, 1981-93 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Carne-Ross, D. S., 1973-82 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Cassity, Turner, 1982, 1984, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Cheney, Brainard, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Church of England. Liturgical Commission, 1993 Feb 1 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Clemo, Jack R., 1977-82 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Cluysenaar, Anne, 1992 Nov 29 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Cody, Richard J., 1975-77, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 67-68)
  - Collecott, Diana, 1989 May 9 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Conquest, Robert, 1981, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Cookson, William
    See: Agenda, box 1, folder 3
  - Corcoran, Neil, 1988 Dec 12 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Core, George, 1984-94 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Costero, Juan Ignacio, 1994-95 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Crozier, Andrew, 1991-93 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Cullingford, Elizabeth
  - Curnow, Allen, 1981-92 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Czerniawski, Adam, 1994 Dec 17 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - "D" general, 1962-95 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Daiches, David, 1980 Oct 2 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Dale, Peter, n.y. Aug 29 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Dawe, Gerald, 1983 Aug 13 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Dekker, George, 1979-94, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Dillon, Millicent, 1981, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Dodsworth, Martin, 1969-93 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    See also: Series IV, University of Oxford Professorship of Poetry, box 28, folder 735
  - Dorn, Edward, 1975-87 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Dubnov, Eugene, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Dudley-Smith, Timothy, 1995 Sep 15 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - DuPlessis, Rachel Blau, 1987 Feb 10 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Dutton, Geoffrey, 1975 Mar 15 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - "E" general, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Edinborough, Arnold, 1973-83 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Edwards, Michael, 1988-95 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Edwards, Philip, 1968-70 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    See also: British Academy, box 1, folder 45
  - Egan, Desmond, 1985 Oct 10 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - England, Eugene, 1992 Jun 25 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Enright, D. J., 1982 Jan 24 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Erskine-Hill, Howard, 1976-94 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Espey, John Jenkins, 1957 Aug 21 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Everett, Barbara, 1982 Apr 25 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - "F" general, 1980-94 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Fainlight, Ruth, 1986 Dec 3 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Feinstein, Elaine, 1977, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Felstiner, John, 1991 Mar 18 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Fisher, Roy, 1973-90 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Flannery, James W.
  - Fontana Paperbacks, 1980 Jan 25 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Foster, Thomas E., 1994 Sep 27 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Freer, Allen, 1983 Mar 14 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Freyer, Grattan
  - Frost, David L., 1993-94 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Furbank, Philip Nicholas, 1975 Jan 9 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - "G" general, 1976-90 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Gale Research Company, 1985 Sep 19 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Genet, Jacqueline
  - Gery, John, 1988 Mar 30 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Gibbons, Reginald, 1971-88 (Box 2, Folder 112-114)
  - Gifford, Henry, 1977-83 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Gioia, Dana, 1980-88 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Golding, Alan C., 1984 Jan 17 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Gordon, David M., 1984 Feb 28 (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Grant, Michael, 1979-94 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Greenbaum, Sidney, 1988 Jul 8 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Greene, Donald Johnson, 1972-83 (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Greene, James, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Griffiths, Eric, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Grosholz, Emily, 1980-90 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    Letter dated 1987 Jul 1 encloses photo.
  - Guérard, Albert J., 1978, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Gunn, Thom, 1969-92, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - "H" general, 1981-92, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Hahn, Claire, 1976-77 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Hall, Donald, 1969-80 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Hamilton, Charles Granville, 1979 Jun 19 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Hamburger, Michael, 1982-95 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Hammond, Gerald, 1991 Nov 12 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    See also: Series II, Books, The Psalms in English, box 12, folder 475
  - Harris, Marguerite, 1976 [Apr] 26 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Hayley, Barbara, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Heaney, Seamus, 1980, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Heard, Alexander, 1988 Feb 22 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Hebert, Ernest, 1970 Dec (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Hergenhan, Laurie, 1975 Feb 9 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Hesse, Eva, 1964-69 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Hillier, Bevis, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Hollander, John, 1969-95 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Holloway, John, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Holroyd, Michael, 1993 May 24 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Hooker, Jeremy, 1979-94, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Hopkins, Justine, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Horovitz, Michael, 1980 Mar 22 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Hough, Graham Goulden, 1966, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Howard, Richard, n.y. Feb 21 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    See also: The New Republic, box 5, folder 219
  - Howe, Irving, 1972 Dec 18 (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - Hulse, Michael, 1983-90 (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - Hutchinson, Roger, 1971 Sep 21 (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - Ironwood (Tucson, Ariz.), 1982 Sep 13 (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - "J" general, 1985, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - Jackson, Gordon, 1992-95 (Box 3, Folder 154-156)
  - Jacobs, Alan, 1992-95 (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - Jarman, Mark, 1987-95 (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - Jeffares, A. Norman
  - Jenkins, Daniel Thomas, 1981-92 (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - Jones, Madison, 1988 Apr 15 (Box 3, Folder 160)
  - Jones, Richard, 1973-94 (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - "K" general, 1984, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - Kavanagh, P. J., 1983-94 (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - Kayman, Martin A., 1991 Mar 25 (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - Kearney, Colbert
  - Kearns, Cleo McNelly, 1987 Aug 23 (Box 4, Folder 165)
  - Kemp, Harry, 1988, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 166)
  - Kenner, Hugh, 1977-87 (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - Kermode, Frank, 1980, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 168)
  - Kiberd, Declan, 1983, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 169)
  - Kinsella, Thomas, 1970-71 (Box 4, Folder 170)
  - Kissane, James D., 1984 Aug 25 (Box 4, Folder 171)
  - "L" general, 1991-94 (Box 4, Folder 172)
  - Lake, Paul, 1981-89 (Box 4, Folder 173-174)
  - Larkin, Philip, 1970, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 175)
  - Lednicki, Waclaw, 1957-58 (Box 4, Folder 176)
  - Lee, John Robert, 1989 Feb 12 (Box 4, Folder 177)
  - Lerner, Laurence, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 178)
  - Levertov, Denise, 1974 Dec 21 (Box 4, Folder 179)
  - Levin, David, 1978 Aug 19 (Box 4, Folder 180)
  - Lewis, Janet, 1958-94 (Box 4, Folder 181-183)
    Letter dated 1958 Dec 26 is a photocopy.
  - Literature and Theology, 1990 Jul 13 (Box 4, Folder 184)
  - Litz, Walt, 1976-86 (Box 4, Folder 185)
  - Livingstone, Angela, 1966-93 (Box 4, Folder 186-187)
  - Logan, Stephen, 1986-90 (Box 4, Folder 188)
  - Lowbury, Edward Joseph Lister, 1991 Apr 8 (Box 4, Folder 189)
  - Lowell, Robert, 1970-71, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 190)
  - Lucas, John, 1983-94 (Box 4, Folder 191)
  - Luce, John Victor, 1982 Oct 7 (Box 4, Folder 192)
  - Lyons, F. S. L., 1969-78 (Box 4, Folder 193)
  - "M" general, 1976-94, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 194)
  - McCormick, Mairi, 1972, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 195)
  - McDonald, Alan, 1987-88 (Box 4, Folder 196)
    See also: John F. Sawyer, box 6, folder 282
  - McGonigal, James, 1995 Aug 10 (Box 4, Folder 197)
  - McGuinness, Patrick, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 198)
  - MacInnes, Mairi
    See: Mairi McCormick, box 4, folder 195
  - McKee, Francis, 1986, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 199)
  - Macrae, Alasdair D. F.
  - Mahon, Derek, 1971, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 200)
  - Makin, Peter, 1987 Feb 19 (Box 4, Folder 201)
  - Manwaring Randle, 1992 Jun 2 (Box 4, Folder 202)
  - Martin, Augustine, 1978-83 (Box 4, Folder 203)
  - Martin, Graham, 1984-94 (Box 4, Folder 204)
  - Martin, Isabel, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 205)
  - Martin, Wallace, 1976-84 (Box 4, Folder 206)
  - Materer, Timothy, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 207)
  - Mathews, Aidan Carl, 1982, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 208)
  - Matthew, H. C. G., 1993 Apr 7 (Box 4, Folder 209)
  - Matthias, John, 1989 Apr 21 (Box 4, Folder 210)
  - Menashe, Samuel, 1979-94 (Box 5, Folder 211)
  - Mercier, Vivian, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 212)
  - Miller, Karl, 1983 Apr 30 (Box 5, Folder 213)
  - Milosz, Czeslaw, 1984 Mar 12 (Box 5, Folder 214)
  - Mitchell Library, Sydney, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 215)
  - Monas, Sidney, 1976 Apr 28 (Box 5, Folder 216)
  - Morse, Ruth
    See: The Cambridge Review, box 1, folder 59
  - "N" general, 1978-84 (Box 5, Folder 217)
  - Needham, John, 1975-83 (Box 5, Folder 218)
  - The New Republic, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 219)
    Contains letters from Richard Howard and Leon Wieseltier.
  - Norris, Leslie, 1991 Jun 17 (Box 5, Folder 220)
  - North Russia Club, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 221)
    Letter dated 1984 Sep 10 encloses group photo.
  - "O" general, 1989 Jan 5 (Box 5, Folder 222)
  - O'Donnell, William H.
  - O'Gorman, Kathleen, 1984, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 223)
  - O'Hara, James Donald, 1976 Apr 22 (Box 5, Folder 224)
  - Oppen, George, 1969-77, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 225)
  - Oxenhorn, Harvey, 1981-86 (Box 5, Folder 226)
  - Oxford University Press, 1976-93 (Box 5, Folder 227)
  - Oxley, William, 1970, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 228)
  - "P" general, 1980-83 (Box 5, Folder 229)
  - Paideuma (Orono, Me.), 1984 Oct 3 (Box 5, Folder 230)
  - Parkinson, Thomas Francis
  - Parnassus: Poetry in Review, 1979-86 (Box 5, Folder 231)
  - Paulin, Tom, 1993 Nov 3 (Box 5, Folder 232)
  - Paz, Octavio, 1971-72 (Box 5, Folder 233)
  - Pearce, Brian Louis, 1983, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 234)
  - Peck, John, 1976-92 (Box 5, Folder 235)
  - Pembroke College (University of Cambridge), 1993 Oct 18 (Box 5, Folder 236)
  - Penberthy, Jenny Lynn, 1990, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 237)
  - Perloff, Marjorie, 1977-84 (Box 5, Folder 238)
  - Philip Larkin Society, 1995 Jul 4 (Box 5, Folder 239)
  - Pinsky, Robert, 1970-93 (Box 5, Folder 240)
  - Poetry Nation Review (Manchester, England)
    See: Michael Schmidt, box 6, folders 284-293
  - Poetry Review (London, England), 1995 Jul 3 (Box 5, Folder 241)
  - Poirier, Richard, 1977 Mar 11 (Box 5, Folder 242)
  - Porter, David T., 1976 Mar 5 (Box 5, Folder 243)
  - Porter, Tony, 1993-94 (Box 5, Folder 244)
  - Pound, Omar S., 1976 Sep 11 (Box 5, Folder 245)
  - Powell, Neil, 1992 Nov 28 (Box 5, Folder 246)
  - Pratt, William, 1984-95 (Box 5, Folder 247)
  - Press, John, 1985-94 (Box 5, Folder 248)
  - Prince, F. T., 1989 Jan 14 (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - Pritchard, William H., 1977-93 (Box 5, Folder 250)
  - Prynne, J. H., 1973 Feb 21 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - Quagliano, Tony, 1988, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 252)
  - Quartermain, Peter, 1984 Jul 30 (Box 5, Folder 253)
  - Quinlan, Kieran, 1983-88 (Box 5, Folder 254)
  - "R" general, 1976-93 (Box 5, Folder 255)
  - Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1972-81 (Box 5, Folder 256)
    Letter dated 1978 Dec 30 encloses photo of her grandson.
  - Raico, Ralph, 1989 Jun 23 (Box 5, Folder 257)
  - Raine, Kathleen, n.y. Sep 23 (Box 5, Folder 258)
  - Rakosi, Carl, 1988 Jun 10 (Box 5, Folder 259)
  - Ramanathan, Suguna, 1976 Dec 24 (Box 5, Folder 260)
  - Randall, Belle, 1984-95 (Box 5, Folder 261-262)
    Letter dated 1990 Sep 19 encloses photo of her children.
  - Rawson, Claude Julien, 1982-91 (Box 5, Folder 263)
  - Read, Richard, 1989, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 264)
    Encloses copy of letter from DD to Adrian Durham Stokes, 1956 May 16.
  - Reck, Michael, 1976-93 (Box 6, Folder 265)
  - Redstone Press, 1990 Jan 19 (Box 6, Folder 266)
  - Reeves, Gareth, 1982-95 (Box 6, Folder 267)
  - Reeves, James, 1973, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 268)
  - Religion and the Arts (Chestnut Hill, Mass.), 1995 (Box 6, Folder 269)
  - Renascence (Milwaukee, Wis.), 1992 Aug 4 (Box 6, Folder 270)
  - Ricks, Christopher B., 1972-89 (Box 6, Folder 271)
  - Robert Graves International Centenary Conference, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 272)
  - Robinson, Peter, 1992-94 (Box 6, Folder 273)
  - Robson, W. W., 1983 Oct 27 (Box 6, Folder 274)
  - Roche, Anthony
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1983 Dec 1 (Box 6, Folder 275)
  - Ross, Alan, 1969-70, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 276)